[Music]
Welcome to business center launch
edition 2025 release wave 2. Today we
will explain new functionality related
to sustainability. This is all existing
functionality across other functionality
in the business central approval
process. So now we enable approvals
across sustainability journal. So my
name is Alexander to product manager. My
colleague
>> Hi, I'm Jacob Bang. I'm also a product
manager and I work with Alexander.
>> So why we did it? We had this journal
earlier but we got feedback that for
bigger companies who need to report they
would like to have this approval process
to improve compliance and control
because maybe one person will collect
all this information but sometimes
because it requires compliance reporting
CSRD or other different types of
reporting it will require to have some
additional control uh before uh it is
posted. So we enable it and we are using
another business value is that yes we
are using standard functionality. So we
didn't try to revent the wheel approval
workflow already exists in the business
central. We just enable this into the
sustainability journal. To do it you
will find the workflow templates. You
will find the new template
sustainability journal batch approval
workflow. You just need to create new
workflow from there and it will work
with few additional configuration as
well. You will see this in a demo.
To use it, you can run from
sustainability journal approval only for
one batch. So not per line, only for
whole batch. And user can choose to send
approval request or to cancel approval
request. It already sent and uh needed
some u improvements. Existing setup as
for all other uh approval workflow. So
definitely nothing new just existing
setup.
Okay, you can show us in the demo.
>> Yeah. So this is just a quick demo just
to illustrate um how that works in
practice because it is very similar to
what you are used to from um existing
workflows. So in this case we go to
workflows we've already established a
sustainability uh workflow template. So
if we go to that we really just enable
it and in this way it will work the same
way as for other approval workflows.
That's how you do it. For the approval
process, we'll go to approval user
setup.
In this case, I am the user. Um,
Alexander is the approver and we already
have that set up in the system.
So, we'll go to the sustainability
journal
and request approval and send the
approval request.
Now the approval request has been sent
and if we go to approvals
we can see that the sustainability
journal batch is ready to approve for
Alexander. So this again is the same way
as for other approval workflows works
the same way in the sustainability hub
as it does in all the other approval
workflows across business central.
>> Thank you Jacob. So you could see how it
works in general standard approval
process. So we have approval setup, we
have workflow and it works from
sustainability journal.
Okay, this is everything about approval
processes sustainability journal. So
before I close this session, general
business central resources, please
remember all of them it can be useful.
Do not forget to subscribe on our
LinkedIn channel to track all weekly
news, other announcements and watch more
videos on YouTube akamsbc YouTube to
watch other sustainability uh videos. We
have many of them, many functionality in
this release plus another features in
this edition in previous editions. So
please go there and watch and learn
more. So thank you for watching this
video.